<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cluster PI – Bash</title>
    <link>/tags/bash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bash on Cluster PI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/bash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Bash</title>
      <link>/docs/prg/bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/prg/bash/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linuxconfig.org/bash-scripting-tutorial&#34;&gt;Bash&lt;/a&gt; it the
command language used in terminal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bash is a shell and is pre-installed. A &lt;em&gt;bash&lt;/em&gt; script contains &lt;em&gt;commands&lt;/em&gt; in
plain text. In order to create a bash script please decide for a
convenient name. Let us assume we name our script &lt;em&gt;myscript&lt;/em&gt;. Than you can
create and edit such a script with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ touch myscript.sh
$ emacs myscripts.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next you need to add the following line to the top ogf the script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;!# /bin/bash
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate how to continue writing a script we will be using the
bash &lt;code&gt;echo&lt;/code&gt; command that allows you to print text. Lets make the second
line&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo &amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now save and start executing your script. Click &amp;ldquo;File&amp;rdquo; and then
&amp;ldquo;Save&amp;rdquo;. Open Terminal and type in &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; followed by the name of the
folder you put the document in. Now we need to execute the script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Executing&lt;/em&gt; a Bash script is rather easy. In order to execute a script,
we need to first execute the &lt;em&gt;permission set&lt;/em&gt;. In order to give Terminal
permission to read/execute a Bash script, you have to type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;chmod u+x myscript.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the script has been granted permission to be executed, you can
test it by typing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./myscript.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;into the terminal. You will see it prints&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hello World
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;osx-terminal&#34;&gt;OSX terminal:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On macOS, when you navigate to the search magnification glass, you can
type in &lt;em&gt;terminal&lt;/em&gt; to start it. A terminal allows you to execute a
number of commands to interact with the computer from a commandline
interface, e.g. the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MOst recently the terminal has in macOS switched from bash to
zsh. Please: consult with zsh tutorials. However the Linux commands
you use in zsh are the same.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
